

PIPARD FABIEN

Software Quality Assurance Developper

fabienpipard@gmail.com

+33 6 33 06 17 98

Age: 30

Localisation: Grenoble, France

CAREER SUMMARY

Software Quality Assurance Developper with over 7+ years of experience in software quality. My various professional experiences have allowed me to obtain expertise in the functionnal or non-fonctionnal test conception and ga tool automation. In order to establish the best quality of a software, it is important to sensitize a team (qa, developer, business analyst, manager) to use

quality processes while trying to respect the principles of agility. Prevention, detection and analysis make it possible to establish the software quality.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Lead

Moodys Analytics - IFRS17 Project

2017 - Present

The IFRS17 project is an application uses Ruby on rails and PostgreSQL for the backend, and the front end is developed with Angular. This application is hosted in an Aure cloud

Developer and QA work with the scrum methodoly and the continuous integration. This project is separated in 3 sub-teams, and I work in a sub-team specialized in the platform conception (architecture, security, performance). I am the QA referent in this sub team and I work with 2 others QA (contractors)

Achievements:

- Elaboration of testing strategy
- Redaction / Execution of manual and automated tests using RSpec Framework
- Redaction / Execution of automated UI tests using Protractor Framework
- Review and analyse defects
- Etablishing cucumber framework for the integration tests and security tests using API:
 - Develop Ruby librairies for the cucumber tests
 - Create script to deploy the cucumber tests with docker
 - Trigger tasks in Continuous integration (TeamCity) to run the cucumber tests
- Create and etablish automated robutness tests:
 - K6 (Load testing)
 - Monkey tests with kubernetes
- Create and etablish automated performance tests
- Support Product team and QA team in Edinburg

Test Frameworks used:



QA Lead

Moodys Analytics - CNSF Regulatory Project

2016- 2017

The CNSF Regulatory project is an apllication uses Ruby and PLSQL. I was QA Lead on this project, the team was componed by 3 developpers and 1 QA. It was a project with short time constraint.

Achievements:

- Elaboration of testing strategy
- Discussion with the Product Team to identify the features and topics for the release
- Redaction / Execution of manual and automated tests using Robot Framework
- Review and analyse defects
- Redaction of delivery documents (Release note, Quality document)
- Organise the meeting project
- Support the product team and the customer implementation team
- Develop Python libraries for Robot Framework

Test Framework used:

Robot Framework

SKILLS & TOOLS

Automation Test Framework

Cucumber
RSpec
Protractor
Protractor
Robot Framework
Report Famework
HP ALM Quality Center
Darfarmanaa Taat Framawark

Performance Test Framework

Jmeter
Jmeter
Locust

Others

Azure	Git	Dock	er	Kuber	netes	Pyth	10
Ruby	Post	greSQL	0	racle	TeamCity		
Jenkins	Per	force	API	Jira	Scr	um	

EDUCATION

DUT IT Science

University Pierre Mendes France - Grenoble 2009 - 2012

Bachelor Science (Ingenery science)

Romans sur Isère

LANGUAGE

French (Native) English (Professional)

INTERESTS

Badminton Hicking Ice Hockey

WORK EXPERIENCE

O QA

Moodys Analytics - RiskIntegrity Standard formula project

2013 - 2016

The RiskIntegrity Standard formula project is an application uses Ruby and PLSQL. I was QA on this project, the team was composed of 12 developers and 5 QA.

Achievements:

- Elaboration of testing strategy
- Redaction / Execution of manual and automated tests using Robot Framework
- Manage QA tools and requests for improvements
- Develop intern libraries for Robot Framework

Test Framework used:

Robot Framework

QA

Sogeti - Biomerieux mission

2012 - 2013

Myla is an appliction developed by Biomérieux, this application is a middleware that collects informations from several medical machinesa. This informations are analysed by the software and identify bactery and cure associated. I was QA (contractor) on this project, the team was composed of 14 developers and 5 QA

Achievements:

- Redaction / Execution of manual tests using TestLink
- Log and review defects in TestLink
- Support external QA team in india

Test Framework used:

TestLink

Software Developer (Internship)

TMM Software (Startup)

2012

The TMM software is used by the patient in a hospital to request services like a TV or payment of cares.

Develop a module to visualize all the options selected by a patient on the TMM Software.

Technologies used:

PHP SQL HTML CSS / JQUERY